Guide to the Jesus Salvador Treviño Papers M0624
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Jesus Salvador Treviño papers
1969-2006
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Treviño, Jesús Salvador
M0624
18 Linear Feet (38 boxes)
Biography
Mexican-American film writer and director, primarily for public television.
Provenance
Gift of Jesus Treviño, 1992-2014.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
Grant proposals, story outlines, script developments and treatments, publicity, soundtracks, videos, etc., all pertaining to the television scripts written and/or produced by Treviño. Includes photographs of Treviño, one by Harry Gamboa.
Television film.; Videorecordings.; Mexican Americans; Photoprints.; Screenwriters.; Mexican American authors; Motion pictures; Mexican American art; Minorities in television.; Mexican Americans and television.; Gamboa, Harry; Solarz, Ken.; Moreno, Eduardo.; Morales, Sylvia.; Lansford, William Douglas.; Torres, Louis R.; Thurman, Jim.; Talbot, David.; Treviño, Jesús Salvador; Zambrano, Jacqueline.; Corr, Eugene.; Zheutlin, Barbara.; Connell, David D.; Vargas, Adolfo.; Castel, Joseph.; Wax, Steve.; Booker, Sue.; Johansen, Jason C.; Grattan, Alejandro.; Franklin, Ricki.
- Accession 1995-089
  - La Historia Thirteen Story Outlines Episodes 1-6 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - La Historia Thirteen Story Outlines Episodes 7-13 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - La Historia, interim report, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - La Historia, 1st Series, "World War 2 and Korea," by Adolfo Vargas. 1979. (not used?) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Quetzalcoatl" - by William Douglas Lansford. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Quetzalcoatl" - by William Douglas Lansford. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Silver Thunderbird" by Eduardo Moreno, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "El Grito de Lares" by Louis R. Torres, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Chapultepec" - by William Douglas Lansford, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Chapultepec" - by William Douglas Lansford, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Chapultepec" - by William Douglas Lansford, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Tierra De Oro" - by Louis R. Torres, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Return" - by Jesus Salvador Trevino, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jose Marti - by Jesus Salvador Trevino, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Aftermath" by Louis R. Torres, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Luis Munoz Marin: 1937 to 1940," by Louis R. Torres, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Luis Munoz Marin: 1937 to 1940," by Louis R. Torres, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Among the Valiant" by Louis R. Torres, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Elena Camacho: Hija de Cuba" by Louis R. Torres, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Ilegal" by Louis R. Torres, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Today, Tomorrow" - by Jesus Salvador Trevino, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - La Historia, 2nd Series, "Herrera!" by Gene Corr, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Sara" by Sylvia Morales 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Adios California" by Jason C. Johansen, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Primo's Odyssey" By Sue Booker 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - including copy of book on which episode was based. Primo's Oddyssey Revised story outline 11/01/80 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "I Was Smart When I Was Nine" by Steve Wax, nd. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Mornin" by Adolfo Vargas 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Joaquin In Aztlan" By Jason Johansen, nd. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Without Their Consent" Sylvia Morales 1979 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - La Historia phase 3. Proposal, January 1981. (Box 3, Item 1)
  - La Historia Phase Three Proposal - June 1981 (Box 3, Item 2)
  - La Historia Phase Three Proposal - June 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - La Historia, script development, December, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Herrera! Teleplay by Eugene Corr, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Herrera! Teleplay by Eugene Corr copy 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - La Historia "Herrera" revised by Alejandro Grattan, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Adios California" Teleplay by Jason C. Johansen (Box 4, Item 5)
  - "Seguin" by Jesus Salvador Trevino November 1979 (Box 4, Item 6)
  - Seguin An Original Teleplay Written by Jesus Salvador Trevino 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - La Historia, "Seguin," 5th revision, July 1980. Film and television works, scripts by Trevino (Box 4, Item 8)
  - The Drop-Out 1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pipeline, First Draft Completed 1980 version (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "The Treaty" 1st draft, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - La Raza History 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - La Raza History 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - La Raza History 1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - La Raza History 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - La Raza History 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - La Raza History 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Yo Soy, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Mexico: the Future, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Vanishing Border, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Vanishing Border, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gabriel's Fire, by Jacqueline Zambrano, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Lifestories, by Ken Solarz, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Mathnet: Despair in Monterey Bay, by David D. Connell & Jim Thurman, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Hero Street, by Joseph Castel & J.S. Trevino, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cancion de la raza, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Science fiction project, proposal by Ricki Franklin, 1990. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Murder at Sleepy Lagoon?, by Louis R. Torres & J.S. Trevino, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Murder at Sleepy Lagoon?, by Louis R. Torres & J.S. Trevino, 1977, copy 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Neighbors: the U.S. and Mexico, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - La Historia, "Chapultepec," by William Douglas Lansford, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Children of the Fifth Sun, by J.S. Trevino, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Children of the Fifth Sun, by J.S. Trevino copy 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Children of the Fifth Sun, by J.S. Trevino, proposal to NEH, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Soldado razo, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Just between friends, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Caminos (magazine), Nov. 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Cine Cubano, [1979], with profile & interview with J.S. Trevino (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - ASI Market Research study of Seguin pilot, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Creative differences: profiles of Hollywood dissidents," by David Talbot & Barbara Zheutlin. Boston, South End Press, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Yo soy Chicano publicity clippings: TV as in LA Times, August 11, 1972 (Oversize-box 9, Item 1)
  - Yo soy Chicano publicity clippings: Eastside Sun, August 10, 1972 (Oversize-box 9, Item 2)
  - Yo soy Chicano publicity clippings: Wyvernwood Chronicle, August 10, 1972 (Oversize-box 9, Item 3)
  - Yo soy Chicano publicity clippings: Community Informer, August 3, 1972 (Oversize-box 9, Item 4)
  - Yo soy Chicano publicity clippings: San Bernandino Sun Telegram TV guide, Aug. 6, 1972 (Oversize-box 9, Item 5)
  - Yo soy Chicano publicity clippings: LA Times TV guide, August 6, 1972 (Oversize-box 9, Item 6)
  - Yo soy Chicano publiLA Times August 10, 1972 (Oversize-box 9, Item 7)
  - Yo soy Chicano publicity clippings: LA Times, August 17, 1972 (Oversize-box 9, Item 8)
  - America Tropical publicity: La Opinion, June 24, 1971 (Oversize-box 9, Item 9)
  - Diez-y-seis publicity: Eastside Sun, Sept. 16, 1971 (Oversize-box 9, Item 10)
  - Diez-y-seis publicity: La Opinion, Sept. 14, 1971 (Oversize-box 9, Item 11)
  - Gangs publicity: Daily Variety, June 2, 1989 (Oversize-box 9, Item 12)
  - Cara exhibit publicity (Oversize-box 9, Item 13)
  - Special issue of La Opinion Sunday supplement titled "Chicano" (Oversize-box 9, Item 14)
  - Cinema primer acercamiento with article by Trevino (Oversize-box 9, Item 15)
  - Raices de Sangre (Oversize-box 9, Item 16)
  - 9 audio tape masters (8 of Yo soy Chicano, 1 of Daniel Valdez America de los Indios concert) (Oversize-box 10, Item 1)
  - 3 Birthwrite audio mix tracks. (Oversize-box 11, Item 1)
  - Photographs: Trevino 1976-77 (Photo by Harry Gamboa) (b+w) (Oversize-box 12, Item 1)
  - Trevino directing, 1992 (Oversize-box 12, Item 2)
  - Trevino directing 1992 (Oversize-box 12, Item 3)
  - Actors in "Seguin" n.d. (Oversize-box 12, Item 4)
  - Newspaper: Nuestro Tiempo, 14 June 1995 (Oversize-box 12, Item 5)
  - Image, parts 1,2,3 ca. 1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 2 Cassettes of Geneoology interviews n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Montevido Cinemateca, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "The Media is the Mistake" Eastside Sun, April 1970. 5 pages (Box 13, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - "Asi is Mi Raza" Text for unpublished photo book. Jan. 1973 6 pages (Box 13, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - "The Legacy of Sleepy Lagoon" (With Luis R. Torres) Nuestro Magazine, November 1977. 3 pages (Box 13, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - "The Mural that Whitewash Could Not Destroy." Nuestro Magazine, February 1978. 2 pages. (Box 13, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - "Desarollo Del Cine Chicano" in El Dia (Mexico City Daily, Sunday Supplement, June 25, 1978. 3 pages. (Box 13, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - "New Mexican Cinema" in Spring, 1979 issue of Film Quarterly, University of California, Berkeley, CA 94720. Pages 26-37. (Box 13, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - "Mexican Cinema-New Directors" in SOMOS magazine, May 1979. Los Angeles, CA 90033. Pages 32-37 (Box 13, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - "Desarrollo Del Cine Chicano" in Formato-16, Ano 2. Num. 5, Dec. 1979. Panama City, Panama. Pages 38-42 (Box 13, Folder 5, Item 4)
  - "Chicano Cinema: A Viewpoint" in Chamba Notes. 3 Pages. (Box 13, Folder 5, Item 5)
  - "Nous Sommes Chicanos" in Le Monde Diplomatique, Paris, France. May, 1980. 1 page. (Box 13, Folder 5, Item 6)
  - "Latino Portrayals in Film and Television" in Hispanic Americans and Mass Media, a publication of the Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, New York, New York for a conference at the Aspen Institute, Colorado, August 2-8, 1980. Pages 71-87. (Box 13, Folder 5, Item 7)
  - "Presencia de Cine Chicano" in La Opinion, Los Angeles, Calfifornia. Sunday Supplement to daily newspaper. Pages 8-9. November 16, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 5, Item 8)
  - "Cinema Chicano aux Etats-Unis" in Les Cinemas De L'Amerique Latine, Pais, France. Edited by Guy Hennebelle. 1980. Pages 492-499 (Box 13, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - "Lo Sviluppo Del Cinema Chicano" in America Latina: Lo Schermo Conteso, publication of the Pesaro Film Festival, Pesaro, Italy. No. 8m 1983. Delivered July, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - "Form and Technique in Chicano Cinema" in Chicano Cinema edited by Gary Keller, Bilingual Review Press. 1985 (Box 13, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - "Chicano Cinema" in The New Scholar, Vol. 8, 1982. Pages 167-180. University of California at Santa Barbara Press, Santa Barbara, CA (Box 13, Folder 6, Item 4)
  - "Chicano Films and Beyond" in Caminos Magazine, Los Angeles, California, Nov. 1982. Pages 6-7, 51. Trevino also co-edited this edition of Caminos Magazine. (Box 13, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - "Presencia del Cine Chicano" in A Traves De La Frontera, Pages 194-200. Published by Centro de Estudios Economicos Investigaciones Esteticas, U.N.A.M. August, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 7, Item 2)
  - "Latinos and PBS: The 2% Factor" in Jumpcut Magazine, Winter, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 7, Item 3)
  - "Latinos and PBS: The 2% Factor" in Caminos Magazine, March, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 7, Item 4)
  - "Guatemalan Refugees: The Tip of the Iceberg." (with Jose Luis Ruiz) in Caminos Magazine, May, 1983. Pages 13-15, 48 (Box 13, Folder 7, Item 5)
  - "Latinos y TV Publica: El Factor de Dos por ciento" in La Opinion. Sunday Supplement to the Los Angeles, Daily, July 10, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 7, Item 6)
  - "Chicano Cinema Overview" in Arieto, Vol. X No. 37. Summer, 1984. Pages 40-43. A Publication of the Circulo de Cultura Cubana, New York, New York (Box 13, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - "Latino Portrayals in Film and TV" in Jumpcut Magazine, March, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 8, Item 2)
  - "Latino Committee Formed" Article in DGA Newsletter June, 1991. 1 Page. (Box 13, Folder 8, Item 3)
  - "Latinos Are Imprisoned By TV's Color Barriers, Too" a counterpunch essay in Calendar section of the Los Angeles Times, June 15, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 8, Item 4)
  - "Looking Beyond the Statistics" article in DGA Newsletter, July, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 8, Item 5)
  - "Light, Camera, Action" essay in the Forum section of Hispanic Magazine, August, 1992. Last page. (Box 13, Folder 8, Item 6)
  - Milwaukee The Beautiful by Dakaota James, May 18, 1986. (Box 13, Folder 9, Item 1)
  - Talking Man by Terry Bisson, Nov. 9, 1986. (Box 13, Folder 9, Item 2)
  - Little Heroes by Norman Spinrad, Dec. 27, 1987. (Box 13, Folder 9, Item 3)
  - La Familia by Robert R. Alvarez, Jr. Sometime in 1988. (Box 13, Folder 9, Item 4)
  - Palm Latitudes by Kate Braverman, August 7, 1988. (Box 13, Folder 9, Item 5)
  - The American Kaleidoscope by Lawrence H. Fuchs, Feb. 10, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 9, Item 6)
  - "The Need for More Spanish American Affairs Programs" 2 Pages. Presentation to the General Assembly of the Public Broadcast Service (PBS) Public Affairs Workshop held in Atlanta, Georgia. September 25, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 10, Item 1)
  - "Chicano Statement to the National Association of Educational Broadcasters," written and sent on behalf of Chicano PBS producers on May 23, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 10, Item 2)
  - "Comentarios de un Cineasta Chicano" Delivered to the General Assembly of the UNAM/CUEC (Universidad Autonoma de Mexico/Centro de Estudios Cinematograficos) Seminar on Latinamerican Cinema. Mexico City, Mexico. August 12, 1974. 2 pages. (Box 13, Folder 10, Item 3)
  - "The Roar of a Mighty River" Delivered to the Annual General Assembly of the Texas Catholic Conference, San Antonio, Texas. September 23, 1974. 4 pages. (Box 13, Folder 10, Item 4)
  - "Interview by Francisco X. Camplis" for his article "Towards A Raza Cinema" Later published in Chicano & Film edited by Chon Noriega, Univ. of Minn. 1992. (Box 13, Folder 10, Item 5)
  - "Cine Chicano" Informe al Comite De Cineastas de America Latina, La Habana, Cuba. June 15, 1978. 6 pages. (Box 13, Folder 11, Item 1)
  - "Hispanics and Public Broadcasting-A History of Neglect" (with Jose Luis Ruiz) A presentation to the Rockefeller Seminar on Independent Television Makers and Public Communications Policy. New York, New York. June 1979. 12 Pages (Box 13, Folder 11, Item 2)
  - Hispanics and CPB: In Quest of National Programming" (with Jose Luis Ruiz) Presentation to the Members of the Board of the Corporation For Public Broadcasting. Washington, D.C. October 17, 1979. Trevino was unable to attend and presentation was made by Carlos Penichet (Box 13, Folder 11, Item 3)
  - "Informe Sobre Cine Chicano" Presentation to the General Assembly of the First Annual Festival of New Latin American Cinema, Dec. 2-16, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 11, Item 4)
  - "Declaracion de Solidaridad del Cine Chicano Con El Nuevo Cine Latinoamericano" Statement by Chicano Delegation to Festival of New Latinamerican Cinema, La Habana, Cuba Dec. 3, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 12, Item 1)
  - "Adapting History to Drama and Making Ends Meet." A Presentation made to the Hispanic Southwest Regional Conference on Media and the Humanities, sponsored by the NEH Media Program. Dec. 4-7, 1980. 11 pages (Box 13, Folder 12, Item 2)
  - "Mexican Cinema at the Crossroads" Presentation to the San Jose Fine Film Society, San Jose Museum of Art, San Jose, California. Feb. 20, 1982. 5 pages. (Box 13, Folder 12, Item 3)
  - "Aesthetics of Chicano Cinema" presentation at the University of California, Berkeley, CA. February 26, 1982. 5 pages. (Box 13, Folder 12, Item 4)
  - "Foreigners in Our Native Land" Presentation at the Film Archives, August 22. 1982. 5 pages (Box 13, Folder 12, Item 5)
  - "North American Media and the Chicano" Presentation to the Seccion de "Los Medios Massivos de Communicacion y La Soberania de los Pueblos," of the Dialogo de las Americas conference, Sept. 9-13, 1982, Mexico City, D.F. Mexico. 5 pages (Box 13, Folder 12, Item 6)
  - "Hacia Una Estructura Dramaurgica Para El nuevo Cine Latinoamericano" (with Alberto Durant) Presentation to the Seminario de Dramaturgia Cinematografica, at the 4th Annual Festival of New Latin American Cinema, La Habana, Cuba. Dec. 3-14, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 1)
  - "Emergence of Chicano Cinema" Regents Lectureship at University of California at Santa Barbara, California, July 12, 1984. 14 Pages. This is a slide presentation that served as the basis for the later presentation at UC Irvine (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 2)
  - "The Chicano Documentary" Regents Lectureship at the University of California at Santa Barbara, California, July 18, 1984. 14 pages (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 3)
  - "The Role of the Chicano Filmmaker" Regents Lectureship at the University of California at Santa Barbara, California, July 19, 1984. 9 pages. (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 4)
  - "Press Statement on behalf of Guadalupe Art Center" San Antonio, Texas. August 24,1984 (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 5)
  - "Chicano Cinema: An Overview" Presentation at Texas Luthern College, Seguin, Texas. May 2, 1985. 14 pages. A variation of the Regents Lecture on Emergence of Chicano Cinema. (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 6)
  - "Making Movies About Mexico" A Presentaion at the University of Texas at El Paso, Texas on the occasion of the screening of Neighbors: The US and Mexico. April 23, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 7)
  - "Vision Historica Del Cine Chicano," Presentation at the University of California, Irvine on the occasion of the Conference on Mexican and Chicano Film, May 18, 1985. 20 Pages. An expanded version of the Santa Barbara Regents Lectureship with emphasis on the impact of new technologies on Chicano filmmaking. (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 8)
  - "The Making of Seguin" Presentation at St. Mary's College Notre Dame, Indiana. Feb. 2, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 9)
  - "Emergence of Chicano Cinema" Presentation at the University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa. February 2, 1989. (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 10)
  - "Chicano Cinema and Social Work" Keynote address to the Trabajadores de La Raza Annual Dinner, Los Angeles, CA. with film clips. October 11, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 11)
  - "Art with a Vision" Keynote address at the 1992 Graduation Ceremonies of Columbia College Hollywood, June 28, 1992. (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 12)
  - "My Teaching Philosophy." Presentation to faculty search committee of USC School of Cinema and Television for Tenure track position teaching directing. March 12, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 13)
  - Biographical Statement 11/06/03 (Box 13, Folder 13, Item 14)
  - (95-089) Scripts for Power, Seaquest, Sweet Justice, Vanishing son, Babylon 5, together with some published material on recent work, 1994-1995 (Box 14)
  - Six videos: Hawkeye - the traitor, Yo Soy Chicano, Seaquest - Sincerest form of flattery, Vanishing son - Birds of Paradise, Best of ahora, Image I (Box 15)
  - Three videos: Seguin, Founding of Texas (Box 16)
  - Five videos: Image, Ahora (Box 17)
  - Three videos: Salazar Inquest (Box 18)
- Accession 1995-258
  - Scripts: Fabulous Sinkhole stories, 5 television episodic scripts (Vanishing Son, Sweet Justice, and 3 for Seaquest), and "Chicano! History of the Mexican American Civil Rights Movement", 1994-1995 (Box 19)
- Accession 1996-152
  - NEW YORK UNDERCOVER, "The Reckoning," 2/14/96 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - NEW YORK UNDERCOVER, "The Reckoning," 2/8/96 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - SPACE: ABOVE AND BEYOND "Stardust" (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - BABYLON 5, "Six Transit Vir" (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - BABYLON 5, "Interludes and Examinations" (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - SWIFT JUSTICE, "Isaiah's Daughter" (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - CHICANO!, #1, 1/19/96 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - CHICANO!, #1, 2/06/96 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - CHICANO!, #2, 1/19/96 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - CHICANO!, #2, 2/06/96 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - CHICANO!, #2, 4/25/96 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - CHICANO!, #3, 1/10/96 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - CHICANO!, #3, 2/06/96 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - CHICANO!, #4, 1/12/96 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - CHICANO!, #4, 2/07/96 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - CHICANO!, #4, 4/29/96 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Top-level design for interactive Chicano series materials (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Preliminary bibliography for Chicano interactive materials (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Preliminary time line for Chicano interactive materials (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - CHICANO! Outreach (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - "Fiesta de los Barrios" literary magazine, 1968-69 (grew out of the high school walkouts in LA) (Box 20, Folder 21)
    Scope and Contents note
    (grew out of the high school walkouts in LA)
  - SEGUIN: first script (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - SEGUIN publicity (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Videocassette of SPACE: ABOVE AND BEYOND "Stardust" (Box 21)
  - Videocassette of NEW YORK UNDERCOVER "The Reckoning" (Box 21)
  - Audiocassette: Interview with Treviño re "The Fabulous Sinkhole" (Box 21)
  - Audio cassette: Treviño's participation on a Raza Pop Quiz program (Box 21)
- Accession 1999-051
  - Shot lists for television programs: (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Diskette 1: Flight, Sons, Voyager, 1996-1997
    - Diskette 2: Correspondence, 1994-1997
    - Diskette 3: NYPD, Sea, Visit, 1994
    - Diskette 4: Begot, Crime, Hope, Super, Voyager, 1996-1997
    - Diskette 5: Begot, Crime, Hope, Mars, Super, Voyager, 1996-1997
  - Diskette 6: Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Diskette 7: Baby, Brain, Company, Court, Soldier, 1995-1996
    - Diskette 8: Babylon, Hawkeye, Running, Siamese, Sweet, 1994-1995
    - Diskette 9: Burning, Pretender, NY, Space, Swift, Voyager, 1996
  - Diskette 10: Burning, Fame LA, Chicago Hope, 1995-1997 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Diskette 11: DGA files, 1994-1996
    - Diskette 12: Honor, Sons & Daughters, White Trash, 1980-1997
    - Diskette 13: Correspondence, 1996
  - 2 audio cassettes of interview with Treviño conducted on Uruguay radio in Montevideo when they did a retrospective of his work, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Articles pertaining to science fiction film work:, 1997-1998 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "Babylon 5 Director's Log" in DREAMWATCH
    - "Behind scenes at Voyager" in SCIENCE FICTION AGE
    - "Visiting Voyager" in SCI-FI UNIVERSE
    - "Jesus Treviño, Director" in STAR TREK VOYAGER
    - "Man of Honour" in DREAMWATCH
    - "Interludes & Examinations"in STARBURST
- Accession 2002-077
  - 4 documents featuring the work of Trevino, 1974-1991 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Publicity materials pertaining to readings/presentations for EYEWITNESS, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Certificates and recognitions, 1996-2001 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - EYEWITNESS; a filmmaker's memoir of the Chicano movement. Houston, Arte Publico Press, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Accession 2007-192
  - Movimiento Epilog Research (I) (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Movimiento Epilog Research (I) (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Movimiento Epilog Research (II) (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Movimiento Epilog Research (II) (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Movimiento Chapters 1-10 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Movimiento Chapters 1-10 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Movimiento Chapters 1-10 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Movimiento Chapters 1-10 A Filmmaker's Recollection of the Chicano Movement (1968-1979) by Jesus Salvador Trevino (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Movimiento Chapters 1-10 A Filmmaker's Recollection of the Chicano Movement (1968-1979) by Jesus Salvador Trevino (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Movimiento Chapters 1-10 A Filmmaker's Recollection of the Chicano Movement (1968-1979) by Jesus Salvador Trevino (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Movimiento Chapters 1-10 A Filmmaker's Recollection of the Chicano Movement (1968-1979) by Jesus Salvador Trevino (4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Movimiento Research Chapters 11-19 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Movimiento Research Chapters 11-19 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Movimiento Research Chapters 11-19 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 14)